What?
什么？
Where are my pants? Where did they go?
我的裤子呢？跑哪里去了？
Better get a move on. I'm gonna be late for the test!
最好快点出发，测验要迟到了
I give up.
我放弃了
What? My pajama pants are gone too.
什么？我的睡裤也不见了？
Good morning, everyone.
大家早
Today is Friday, July 26. Ten'ei 18.
今天是天永18年7月26日星期五
Oh, right! I'll just borrow them from Mimihime!
对了，我可以借穿弥美姬的
What?
什么？
Everyone! Do you want to go outside of the outside?
各位，你们想去外面的外面吗？
-Yes! I do! -What?
-想，我们想 -什么？
-I want to. -Then, I do too!
-我想 -那我也想
Me too.
我也想
Then we will begin the test.
那么，测验开始
What a weird dream.
好奇怪的梦啊
My hair is so short!
我的头发好短
Oh, right. I had it cut yesterday.
对了，我昨天剪头发了
Good morning, everyone.
大家早
Today is Friday, July 26. Ten'ei 18.
今天是天永18年7月26日星期五
The same date as in my dream.
我的梦境也是这一天
Hey, why are you so depressed lately?
你最近怎么闷闷不乐的？
We still don't know anything about the test.
对于测验的内容，我仍然一无所知
Yeah, but Tokio's coming back today!
对啦，但时男今天要回来了
Yeah, we get to hang out with Tokio again.
对呀，我们又能跟时男一起玩了
Danger.
危险
-What? -Danger.
-什么？ -危险
Danger. Danger.
危险，危险
Access failed.
登入失败
Most of Mina's systems are down.
美娜大部分的系统都挂了
Looks like the terminal still works.
看来终端机仍然正常
Can't we use that instead?
改用那个不行吗？
I've been trying that, but…
我一直在试，但是…
SANCTUM
（昇殿室）
Access failed.
登入失败
-Danger. Danger. Danger. -Access failed.
-危险…危险 -登入失败
Access failed.
登入失败
-Danger. Danger. Danger. -Access failed.
-危险…危险 -登入失败
-Hello? Can you hear me?
-喂？听得到我的声音吗？
Hey! Hello?
喂？
It really is dangerous!
真的很危险
Wait, this area…
等等，这个区域…
It kind of smells like food.
闻起来有食物的味道
FISH - MEAT - SAKE
（鱼，肉，清酒）
-For real? -It's a market!
-不是吧？ -是市场耶
It's way bigger than just a "settlement."
这里的规模远比聚落大多了
Why have so many people come to this place?
为什么有这么多人来这里？
FUEL - FISH - FOOD GRADE MEAT
（燃料，鱼，食用肉）
It's as booming as the Asakusa Racecourse.
就跟浅草赛道一样热闹
FOOD GRADE MEAT - DRIED MEAT
（食用肉，肉干）
SALTED MEAT AND POTATO SOUP ONE CHIP
（腌肉土豆汤） （一枚代币）
Since we're here, wanna eat? Sis?
我们既然都来了，想吃吗，姐？
-Come and look! -Please come again!
-来看看哦 -欢迎再度光临
Good idea.
好主意
If this is a dream, better eat before we wake up.
如果这是一场梦，最好在醒来之前吃一顿
Excuse me, two portions of this one, please.
不好意思，这个请给我两份
Sure.
没问题
ASAKUSA OKONOMIYAKI
（浅草御好烧）
It's illegal to use the old paper money here.
在这里使用旧纸钞是非法的
Don't you have any chips?
你没有代币吗？
Chips?
代币？
It's the town's currency.
这个城镇的货币
If you register as a visitor, you'll get five chips each.
如果你以访客的身份注册 每人就可得到五枚代币
For free?
免费的？
-Where do we need to go? -The Ministry of Reconstruction.
-该去哪里注册？ -复兴省
The Ministry of Reconstruction?
复兴省？
There's really a Ministry of Reconstruction?
复兴省真的存在哦？
MINISTRY OF RECONSTRUCTION
（复兴省）
So it really exists.
真的存在哦
What's the Ministry of Reconstruction?
复兴省是什么？
You've never heard of it?
你从没听说过？
BUILDING MAP DO NOT ENTER
（蓝图） （禁止进入）
The mysterious disappearances, kidnappings, or ghost stories?
失踪谜团、绑架或者鬼故事？
JOB BOARD
（工作栏）
They're hiring engineers to restore the old civilization.
他们正在应征复兴旧文明的工程师
INVESTIGATION - HEALTH
（调查，健康）
Could just be a vigilante group that stole the name from the rumors.
可能只是盗用这个名字的义警队
RESIDENTS ONLY - RECEPTION
（居民专用窗口，接待柜台）
That might be true.
可能是如此
But this town has actually been restored.
但这个小镇还真的复苏了
Maybe it's not a shady organization, then.
或许这并不是一个糟糕的组织
Well, rumors always get exaggerated.
谣言总是会被夸大
Are you travelers?
你们是游客吗？
Yes, exactly.
对，没错
Can we have some chips?
请给我们一些代币吧
HARUKI TAKEHAYA - GENDER AGE: 18 - BLOOD TYPE: ?
（竹早春希，性别） （18岁，血型？）
MARU - MALE - AGE: 15 APPLYING FOR: MYSELF
（小丸，男性） （15岁，本人申请）
Okay, you're all set.
好的，这样就可以了
This is the currency for the town.
这是这个城镇的货币
Don't take notice of the different colors.
别在意有各种颜色
They're all the same.
全都是一样的
-Let's take this and go eat! -And this is--
-拿这些去大吃一顿吧 -这是…
Actually, I've got a question.
等等，我其实有个问题
You have every resident's face on record, right?
这里的每位居民都有相片纪录，对吧？
Do you know the man in this picture?
你认识照片上的男子吗？
Or this face?
或者是这张脸？
Oh, my.
我的天
This man. What's his name?
这个人，他叫什么名字？
Robin Inazaki.
稻崎露敏
How do you know him?
你怎么会认识他？
I-Is Robin here?
露敏在这里吗？
Let me see him!
让我见他一面
We're friends! No, we're family!
我们是朋友，不，我们是家人
Do you mind calling to ask?
方便请你打去问一下吗？
Sure.
好的
This is the Ministry of Reconstruction.
这是复兴省
Please tell the chief he has a guest.
请通知首领，他有访客
She has his photo and says she's a family member.
她拿着他的相片说她是亲友
She didn't leave a last name,
她没说她贵姓
but it's a young woman called Kiruko.
是个叫贵留子的年轻女性
Yes, thank you.
好的，谢谢
I'll let her know.
我会转达她
I made an appointment for you.
我帮你预约好了
It's in two hours at the Large Filtration Plant.
两个小时后在大型过滤厂
But, where's the Large Filtration Plant?
是说，大型过滤厂在哪里？
That's the Large Filtration Plant across the river.
河的对面就是大型过滤厂
That's exactly where Takahara Academy's Ibaraki Facility is.
高原学园的茨城设施就是在那里
The appointment's not for two hours, so we'll have to sleep round here tonight.
距离会面时间还有两小时 所以今晚我们得在附近过夜
RENTAL 0021
（出租0021）
Oh, I see.
原来如此啊
We need to hang this up outside wherever we decide to sleep.
我们决定要睡觉的时候 就得把这个挂在外面
So if you see one of these, there's already someone living there.
所以如果你见到这种牌子 就表示里面有人住了
Let's stay here! Looks like no one's using it.
在这里待下来吧，看来这里没人
How sophisticated.
好精致啊
It feels so civilized.
感觉好文明哦
When people gather together in one place,
当人们聚集在同一个地方时
it creates a totally different lifestyle to scavenging around.
就会创造出一种与四处搜刮资源 完全不同的生活方式
I guess people are gonna gather in one place like this more and more,
我想会有越来越多人聚集在这样的地方
fixing and rebuilding stuff, rather than squandering all the resources.
做修复和重建的工作 而不是把资源都浪费掉
Sis, you're talking to yourself a lot. You're being weird.
姐，你一直在自言自语，你怪怪的
It's okay. You want to go alone, right?
没关系的，你想自己一个人去，对吧？
Sorry. I'm supposed to be your bodyguard.
抱歉，我应该是你的保镖才对
And you're the reason we were heading to that place.
因为你的缘故，我们才会前往那个地方
The guy you've been looking for all these years could be there.
你这些年一直在找的那个人可能就在那里
It's not your fault.
这不是你的错
Go and take a look first.
你先去看看吧
I'll be back, so make sure you wait for me.
我会回来的，你一定要等我回来
LARGE FILTRATION PLANT
（大型过滤厂）
Robin.
露敏
What? What happened?
怎么了？发生了什么事？
Is this the "Spear of Heaven" the Director spoke of?
这就是园长提过的「天国之矛」吗？
What is this?
这是什么？
Did a plane fall on us?
飞机坠落到我们身上了吗？
I'm sure I saw it for a split second.
我确定我在一瞬间看到了它
It's an attack on Takahara!
这是对高原的袭击
To the back of the building! Hurry!
到建筑物后方，快点
It's as if they were waiting for me to return!
他们一副等着我回来的样子
Shiro!
士郎
It's nothing.
这没什么
Hey, you okay?
你还好吗？
Let's get out of here.
我们快点离开这里
Hey, nobody from Michika's year is here!
与美智香同年级的学生都不在这里
They should've been in swim class.
他们应该在上游泳课
That's right.
是哦
Everyone, take cover at the pool!
各位，快去泳池躲起来
That's probably the safest spot.
那里可能是最安全的地方
You're not coming with us, Mimihime?
弥美姬，你不跟我们一起去吗？
There's something I want to check out.
我想确认一件事
The wall, right?
那面墙，对吧？
Right. There was a hole in the wall.
是说，那面墙有一个洞
You all saw it too?
你们也都看到了？
Let's go together.
我们一起去吧
Okay.
好
I'm gonna look for Tokio after taking them to safety.
带他们去到安全的地方之后 我要去找时男
Okay.
好的
Then I'll see you at the pool.
那我们等等泳池见
Push the chair! Quickly!
推轮椅，快点
Geez.
天啊
You're so useless!
你真没用
You can run?
你能跑？
Which one's which? I can't tell!
谁是谁呀？我分不出来
Wait. Wait.
等等，等等
I can just test them when the system comes back online.
等系统重新连线之后，我就能测试他们
All right.
好的
What's going on?
到底是怎么回事？
We're investigating it!
我们正在调查
Is it over?
结束了吗？
Look at this mess.
真是一团乱
Maybe something exploded?
可能是某个东西爆炸了吗？
Let's ask the teachers later.
等等问老师
Let's take a look at that hole first.
先去看看那个洞吧
I've always wondered if there was something beyond the wall.
我一直想知道墙外是否有什么东西
Me too.
我也是
TAKAHARA ACADEMY IBARAKI FACILITY
（高原学园） （茨城设施）
Sorry for the wait.
抱歉让你久等了
Robin!
露敏
What are you doing here, Robin?
你在这里做什么，露敏？
Why haven't--
为什么…
What about the orphanage?
孤儿院怎么办？
Calm down.
冷静
Let's take our time talking.
有话慢慢说
We both have a lot of questions.
我们都有很多问题
Still, I can't just believe something like that immediately.
但是，我仍然没办法马上就相信这种事
How could your mind be in Kiriko's body?
你的心智怎么可能在桐子的身体里？
I'm looking at Kiriko when I'm talking to you like this.
当我像这样跟你说话的时候 我见到的是桐子
But your expressions are just like Haruki's.
但你的表情就跟春希一模一样
They're Haruki's facial tics.
春希的脸部才会这样抽动
You've got Kiriko's voice. But the way you speak is like Haruki.
你有桐子的声音 但你说话的方式就跟春希一样
I see. Your mind, huh?
我懂了，你的心智是吗？
But Sakota could definitely do it.
但佐古田肯定办得到
Sakota? Is that the Doc?
佐古田？是那位医生吗？
Do you know where he is?
你知道他在哪里？
Nope. No clue.
不，我不知道
I left Asakusa looking for him. But I lost him.
我为了找他离开了浅草 但我失去了他的下落
And Funayama Orphanage was gone by the time I came back to Asakusa.
我回到浅草之后，船山孤儿院就消失了
Then a bunch of other things happened.
然后各种事情接踵而来
-I met Usami. -Really?
-我遇到宇佐美了 -是哦？
Is the person who was with Usami still alive?
跟宇佐美在一起的人还活着吗？
She was when we first met.
我们刚遇见他的时候还活着
I was staying at Usami's place until two years ago.
直到两年前，我都一直待在宇佐美那里
Then I found this place.
然后我发现了这个地方
What is this place?
这是什么地方？
There's a bunch of documents that look like plant research.
有很多看起来像是研究植物的文件
You're pretty smart.
你相当聪明
It seems that, before the Great Disaster, they genetically engineered plants
在大灾难发生之前 他们似乎在对植物进行基因改造
to make them edible and resistant to harsh climates.
让它们可以食用并且能够抵抗极端气候
Look.
你看
They started growing like crazy once we fixed up the fields.
我们把田地整修完成之后 它们就疯了似地生长
Then people started settling here.
然后大家开始移居来此
And among those people-- You saw them, right?
在那些居民当中，你见到他们了，对吧？
Some guys from the Ministry of Reconstruction.
有些来自复兴省的人
After that, it quickly turned into a real town.
这里很快地就转变成一个真正的城镇了
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
（仅限授权人员）
This place is called the Large Filtration Plant
这个地方叫做大型过滤厂
because we fixed it up so that we can manually filter the water from the river.
我们把它整修过了 所以我们可以用手动操作的方式过滤河水
The Ministry also got the plant to boil water and generate power.
复兴省还让工厂能够煮水和发电
That's where all the electricity used in this facility comes from.
这个设施所需的电力就是来自于此
It's getting cold.
变冷了
HOT BATH
（热水池）
Take a bath before you go. I already filled the tub.
离开之前冲个澡吧 我已经帮你放好热水了
I still have questions!
我还有问题
I know.
我知道
It's been five years.
已经五年了
Let's take our time.
我们慢慢来吧
O-Okay.
好的
Let's play rock, paper, scissors to choose who goes to look.
我们用石头剪子布来决定谁先去探路吧
Mimihime!
弥美姬
When you shower, run the cold water, then add hot water slowly.
你洗澡的时候，先开冷水 再慢慢加入热水
You'll burn yourself if you start with the hot water.
如果你先开热水的话，会烫伤自己
Got it.
懂了
I knew Robin was amazing.
我就知道露敏最棒了
He was able to make a town that has both water and food.
他能够打造出一座有水有食物的小镇
It's like heaven.
就跟天国一样
I was afraid.
我好害怕
I was so scared.
非常害怕
But it's fine now.
但现在没事了
Now…
现在…
I'll have Robin.
我有了露敏
Will Sis be okay without this?
姐没把这个带在身上可以吗？
Wow! There are two hair dryers!
有两支吹风机耶
I'm dual wielding!
我也可以二刀流
What?
奇怪
Robin! My clothes are gone!
露敏，我的衣服不见了
Hey! I've warmed up the room. Just come like that.
我把房间弄暖和了，你就直接过来吧
Kiriko.
桐子
No, you're Haruki.
不，你是春希
You're both really interesting kids.
你们两个都是很有趣的孩子
From the bottom of my heart,
我收留了你们两人
I'm truly happy I picked you both up.
让我打从心底感到非常开心
What is this place?
这是什么地方？
Inside the school's outer wall
在学校的外墙内
is another outside!
是另一个外面
Oh, wow!
唉哟
The ceiling is
天花板…
so high!
好高
I thought I was falling up.
我以为我要摔倒了
Thanks for your business!
谢谢惠顾
SALTED MEAT AND POTATO SOUP YUMMY DELICIOUS SOUP
（腌肉土豆汤） （美味好喝的汤）
PLEASURE BAR
（欢乐酒吧）
Hey, handsome, how about a drink?
帅哥，要不要喝一杯呀？
You can bring that in with you.
你可以把那个一起带进来
No, thanks. I'm gonna eat at home.
不用了，谢谢，我要回家吃
Can I even eat all this by myself?
我一个人吃得完吗？
You've grown so much since we last saw each other.
跟我们上次见面比起来，你长大了好多
You're covered in scars. It must've been hard.
你全身都是疤痕，一定很辛苦吧
Robin! What is this? Stop it!
露敏，你在做什么？住手
What? I'm just conducting a small experiment.
怎么了？我只是在做个小实验
Who's inside this head of yours?
在你脑子里的人到底是谁？
I said. It's me!
我说过了，是我
Say your name.
说出你的名字
It's Haruki!
我是春希
Really?
是吗？
All right. Take a look in the mirror.
那好，去照照镜子吧
Who's on the bed with me?
跟我在床上的人是谁？
Who is that girl?
那个女孩是谁？
S-Sis.
是姐
Right! It's the sister you love so much.
没错，是你深爱的姐姐
She's about to be held by another man.
她就要被另一个男人抱住了
Shouldn't you save her?
你不该救她吗？
Stop it.
住手
Robin, why are you…
露敏，你为什么…
Now, whose body am I touching?
我现在摸的是谁的身体？
Tell me, Haruki.
告诉我，春希
Robin…
露敏
Haruki.
春希
HARUKI TAKEHAYA - GENDER AGE: 18 - BLOOD TYPE
（竹早春希，性别） （18岁，血型）
Robin!
露敏
No.
不行
Not me. Look in the mirror, Haruki.
别看我，看着镜子吧，春希
Watch what I'm gonna do to your sister.
看看我会对你姐做出什么事
It's so blue and dazzling.
好蓝好耀眼
It's so pretty.
好漂亮
OUTSIDE OF THE OUTSIDE
（外面的外面）